THIS STORY IS A FICION, AND ALL NAMES OF FIGURES ND ORGANIZATIONS ARE FICTITIOUS.
（本作所有人物、组织名均为虚构 与任何特定事件或现象无关）
No… My Lady is being bestowed?
不是吧 娘娘要被赏赐给别人了？
I understand.
我明白了
-Lady Fuyou! -Please wait!
-芙蓉娘娘 -请等一下
Oh! So cold…
好冷哦
It's been a while since we came to the capital,
我们来到中枢也好一段时间了
but it's hard to get used to the chilly mornings.
但还是很不习惯冷冽的早晨
I miss our homeland's sand and sunshine.
我好想念家乡的沙和阳光
The Western Capital was also chilly in the mornings and evenings.
西都的早晚也很冷
The Western Capital, huh?
西都？
It feels so nostalgic now.
还真是让人怀念
It feels like we arrived just yesterday
我们陪着玉叶娘娘入宫
for Lady Gyokuyou to enter the court.
彷佛是昨天的事
That reminds me. Father was pleased in his letter.
那提醒我了 爸爸在信上显得挺高兴的
Commerce between the Western Capital and the central area is increasing.
西都和中枢之间的 贸易往来愈来愈活络了
It's because Lady Gyokuyou is loved!
那是因为玉叶娘娘很受宠
It's the homeland of the Emperor's favorite.
那是皇上宠妃的故乡
Even the central area can't ignore that.
就连中枢也不能忽视那里
Are you cleaning the kitchen?
膳房打扫干净了吗？
We'll help too.
我们也可以帮忙
We'll never finish unless we split tasks.
不分工合作 我们绝对做不完
We can't ask the other palace women.
我们不能请其他宫女帮忙
Remember when we found poisoned needles in her clothes?
还记得我们在 娘娘的衣服里发现毒针的事吗？
It was especially bad when she was pregnant.
在娘娘怀孕的时候 状况尤其糟糕
Part of that may be because she's a foreign princess.
部分原因也许是出于她是异族公主
It'll be okay. We have a new attendant, remember?
现在没事了 有一位新侍女来了 记得吗？
Maomao, what are you making?
猫猫 你在做什么？
Cold medicine.
感冒药
You can make that?
你连感冒药也会做？
Our new attendant is talented.
我们新来的侍女很有才能
Hey, do you need my help with anything?
有什么需要我帮忙的吗？
Are you eating well?
你吃得好吗？
I am, thank you.
很好 谢谢
You can always talk to me, all right?
有什么话都可以跟我说 好吗？
Yes…
好…
Hey, have you heard?
对了 你听说了吗？
There's a new rumor going around recently.
最近出现了一个新的谣言
No.
没听说
There's a ghost in the rear palace.
后宫出现了幽灵
A ghost?
幽灵？
I know! It's the white lady ghost!
我知道 是白衣女鬼
So it's famous?
她很有名？
All the palace women, eunuchs, and concubines are talking about it.
所有的宫女、宦官和娘娘 都在谈论这件事
It's been about two weeks.
已经有两周了
They say a ghost of a white lady
他们说有个白衣女鬼
has been seen dancing in midair under the moon.
会衬着月光在半空中跳舞
It's every night by the castle walls at the Eastern Gate!
每个晚上在东大门的城墙都看得到
I see.
是哦
The castle walls surround the entire rear palace.
整个后宫都有围墙包围着
You can only enter and leave through the gates
进出只能通过位于东、西、南、北
of the four directions, East, West, South and North.
四个方向的大门
Yeah, right.
没错
There's always guards at the castle gates,
大门口总是有卫兵驻守
and there's a deep moat outside.
而且外面有一条很深的护城河
It's impossible to escape or sneak in.
根本不可能逃出去或溜进来
It's said that buried deep inside the moat are
据说护城河深处埋着一位
the remains of a concubine who tried to escape the rear palace…
试图逃离后宫的娘娘的遗骸
In other words, a typical ghost story.
我猜这不过是个老套的鬼故事
What should I do if I see a real ghost?
如果看到幽灵的话 我该怎么办？
It's just a rumor.
那只是个谣言
Excuse me. Will you look at my medicine?
不好意思 方便请你看一下我的药吗？
Oh, it's you, miss! Give me a second.
小姑娘 是你啊 等我一下
It's almost like he was wasn't suspicious of me just the other day.
他一副前几天没有怀疑过我的样子
Ever since he realized I can make medicine,
自从他发现我会调药之后
he lets me prepare it.
他就随我这么做了
He even shares with me the ingredients I need.
他甚至会分享一些我需要的药材
He even gives me tea.
还会请我喝茶
Is he allowed to be this laid back?
他这么悠哉没问题吗？
Sorry for the wait.
久等了
Wow!
哇
You like salty things more than sweet things, right?
比起甜品 你更喜欢咸点 对吧？
I'd like some of those too.
我也想吃一些
Right away!
马上给您准备
Thank you for your hard work.
你辛苦了 谢谢
It's not that bad.
也没那么辛苦啦
Does this guy have nothing to do?
这个人闲闲没事做吗？
A eunuch should be at the Domestic Service Department!
宦官应该待在内侍省才对
Instead, he just wanders around
但他却跑来跑去
as if he's keeping watch over the entire rear palace….
彷佛在监视着整座后宫一样…
In that case, he's higher up
这样的话 他的地位
than the Matron of the Serving Women!
就比宫官长更高咯？
He could be the guardian of the Emperor,
他可能是皇上的禁军
but he's too young for that.
但他的年纪又太小了
He must be the Emperor's lover!
他一定是皇上的爱人
I feel like you're thinking about something very rude.
我觉得你在想一些非常失礼的事
You must be imagining it.
那是你的错觉吧
Doctor, I'm very sorry. Can you get these for me?
医官 不好意思 可以麻烦你给我准备这些吗？
So, what do you want to discuss?
你想跟我讨论什么事？
Do you know about the ghost incidents?
你知道幽灵的事吗？
I've heard the rumors.
这个谣言我听说了
And what about somnambulance?
那梦游症呢？
Somnambulance?
梦游症？
So you are interested.
你感兴趣咯
How does one heal that?
梦游症要如何治疗？
I don't know.
我不知道
It's not something to heal with medicine.
用药物是治不好的
So you can heal it without medicine?
所以你不用药物就能治好梦游症？
I only work with medicine.
我只会用药物
I'm at a loss.
我很烦恼
I'm truly at a loss.
我真的很烦恼
So annoying! What a stubborn man!
烦死人了 这男的纠缠不休
I'll try my best.
我会尽力试试看
He's different from the other eunuchs.
他跟其他的宦官不太一样
Miss Maomao.
猫猫大人
No need for honorifics.
不需要对我这么尊敬
Your position is much higher than mine, Sir Gaoshun.
高顺大人 您的位阶比我高
In that case, Xiaomao.
这样的话 小猫…
Xiao? So now I'm a little girl?
小？我现在成了小姑娘咯？
Will you stop regarding Sir Jinshi
你看壬氏大人的眼光 可以不要一副
as if he's a caterpillar?
他是条毛毛虫的样子吗？
Shit! He knows!
可恶 他知道了！
Just today, he came back
今天他回来之后
and told me in a happy state that you regarded him
很开心地告诉我 你看他的眼光
as if he were a caterpillar.
彷佛他是一条毛毛虫
I'll be careful from now on.
之后我会注意的
Anyone without enough practice
训练不足的话
could get dizzy and collapse.
可能会感到头晕和虚脱
People have all kinds of kinks, huh?
人类有各种各样的怪癖 对吧？
Here we are.
就是这里
A Chinese hibiscus under the moon…
月下芙蓉…
You have a keen eye.
你眼力真好
That is Concubine Fuyou,
那是芙蓉妃
a mid-ranking concubine
她是中级妃
who will be bestowed to a soldier as a reward next month.
下个月就会赏赐给一名武官
I think it's been two years.
已经两年了吧
She's a very timid princess.
她是一位非常胆怯的公主
She's a good dancer,
她很会跳舞
but made a mistake performing in front of the Emperor.
但在皇上面前表演时出了差错
She's had no visits from the Emperor since entering the court,
从她进入后宫之后 皇上从没临幸过她
and stayed shut inside her room.
成天关在房里
It's no one's fault, but even so…
那不是任何人的错 但就算如此…
-To be bestowed… The poor girl. -Lady Fuyou!
-居然被赏赐出去了 好可怜 -芙蓉娘娘
So the somnambulance is caused by her agony over being bestowed?
所以她是因为被赏赐而感到痛苦 因此导致了梦游症？
The illness is said to be caused by a loss of balance in the mind…
这种病据说是出于精神不稳定
No, I need more information.
不行 我需要更多信息
I'll go see her one more time.
我要再去看她一次
Where is Concubine Fuyou's room?
芙蓉妃的居所在哪里？
Her outbuilding is to the north.
她的楼房在北侧
Thank you very much. And for the tea, also.
感激不尽 也谢谢您招待的茶水
You're already going?
你要走了？
I hope she cheers up.
我希望她能振作起来
She's a princess from a small vassal state.
她是某蕞尔小国的公主
She may not want to go back.
她可能是不想回去
Go back?
回去？
Oh, the thing is…
是这样的…
Poor Concubine Fuyou.
可怜的芙蓉妃
Yes. To be bestowed to a soldier.
对呀 被赏赐给一名武官
Just thinking about it scares me!
光用想的就让我头皮发麻
She has a very different impression than
她现在的模样跟在城墙边
when she was dancing on the castle walls.
跳舞的时候比起来判若两人
Yes.
对
I was surprised myself when I saw her dance for the first time.
当我第一次看到她跳舞的时候 我也大吃一惊
She's usually more simple-looking.
她平时的容貌看起来很平凡
She's really like a Chinese hibiscus flower.
她真的很像一朵芙蓉花
-A flower? -Yes.
-一朵花？ -对
Chinese hibiscus flowers
芙蓉花
blossom into a large white flower in the morning.
会在早上绽放出白色的大花瓣
However, in the evening,
然而 到了晚上
the color changes into a dark pink color.
颜色就会变成暗粉红
So it's a flower that has many faces in a single day?
所以是在一天当中 有好几种模样的花朵？
Exactly.
正是
The ghost story?
幽灵的事？
Yes. I wanted to hear more about it.
对 我想知道更多幽灵的事
Do you know anything?
你有听说什么吗？
Now that I think about it,
听你这么一说
I heard the ghost appeared first on the northern side.
我听说幽灵首先是从北侧出现的
-The north? -Xiaolan? Here's your laundry!
-北侧？ -小兰 你的衣服来了
-Coming! -She moved from the north to the east?
-我来了 -她从北侧移到了东侧？
Oh, the thing is…
是这样的…
I see, I thought so. So Concubine Fuyou is…
原来如此 跟我想得一样 所以芙蓉妃她…
Old man would tell me not to act on speculation.
老爹会叫我别被猜测牵着鼻子走
Somnambulance is a mysterious illness.
梦游症是个谜样的疾病
It's said to be caused by an unbalanced heart.
有人说是由于精神不稳定所造成的
A patient acts as if they're awake even when they're asleep.
尽管病人的行为彷佛是醒着的 他们仍然处于睡眠状态
Back at the brothel,
我还在青楼的时候
there was a courtesan afflicted by the same illness.
有位青楼女子也得过梦游症
She was a cheerful courtesan talented at poetry.
她是一位开朗的青楼女子 很会作诗
There were talks of her being bought out.
大家都在说有人即将给她赎身
This offer was eventually rescinded.
赎身之事最后告吹了
She started wandering around the brothel every night,
她开始每晚在青楼里游荡
as if she were possessed by a ghost or demon.
彷佛她被幽灵或恶魔附身了
Oh. What's wrong, everyone?
大家是怎么了？
The courtesan in question had no memory of the night at all.
这位有问题的青楼女子 完全不记得晚上发生的事
So, what happened?
然后呢？
Nothing. She stopped wandering around
没有然后了 赎身之事告吹之后
when her offer was rescinded.
她就不再游荡了
So you mean that the courtesan didn't
所以你的意思是说
want to get bought out?
她不想被赎身？
Most likely.
很有可能是这样
The man was a large store owner.
那个男人有一间很大的店铺
He not only had a wife and kids, but even grandchildren.
他不仅早已有老婆孩子 甚至还有孙子
And she only had a year left in her term of service.
而且她只要在青楼再待一年 就能约满离开
Maybe it's the same with Concubine Fuyou.
也许芙蓉妃也是类似的状况
Is that really all?
真的就只有这样？
Yes.
对
Really?
真的吗？
Calm down!
冷静一点
I'm going back to work.
我要回去工作了
After that, Concubine Fuyou was prohibited from going outdoors.
在那之后 芙蓉妃就被禁止出门
She was to be guarded by an eunuch
在她被赏赐的日子到来之前
until the day of her bestowment arrived.
门口都有卫兵看守着
I hope this goes well.
真希望一切顺利
Isn't Maomao acting a bit strange these days?
这些天来 猫猫的行为举止是不是有点奇怪？
Is she?
有吗？
I knew it. There's something else to this.
我就知道 此事另有蹊跷
Is today Concubine Fuyou's day of departure?
今天是芙蓉妃离开的日子吗？
That's what I heard.
我听说是这样
-Hey. -Huh?
-猫猫 -什么？
Don't you think you could at least tell me
你不觉得至少该把事情的真相
what the real story is?
告诉我吗？
I'm the one asking you. I won't get angry.
是我主动问你的 我不会生气
These are just speculations.
这些都只是我的猜测
Please don't tell anyone about this.
请不要告诉别人
I'm very tight-lipped.
我的口风很紧
Do you remember the story of the courtesan I told everyone?
您记得我告诉大家 有关那名青楼女子的事吗？
-The one with the somnambulance? -Yes.
-有梦游症那个？ -对
There was one other courtesan whose proposal was rescinded
有另外一位青楼女子 也是出于同样的原因
due to the same illness.
导致赎身告吹
That courtesan ended up
那位青楼女子最后
receiving a new proposal to be bought out,
还是遇到了一个愿意给她赎身的人
but because she was a courtesan with an illness,
但因为她是个有病在身的青楼女子
the total sum was half the silver of the original proposal.
赎身的银两变成只有原本的一半
But this was all an act.
但这是一场骗局
An act?
骗局？
The two men who proposed to buy out the same woman
这两位提出要给这名女子赎身的男子
knew each other.
彼此认识
The woman pretended to be ill
这名女子装病
so that the first proposal would be rescinded.
所以第一次的赎身提议因此告吹
Later, the man who was truly interested bought her out
之后 真正想要替 这名女子赎身的男子
at half the original price.
用一半的银两成功替她赎身
For them to be together, he didn't have enough silver,
他想跟她在一起 但他没有这么多银子
and she still had a long term of service.
而且她的卖身契还有很久才到期
You're saying Concubine Fuyou is the same as that courtesan?
你的意思是说芙蓉妃 跟这名女子状况类似？
The soldier who'll be with Concubine Fuyou
得到赏赐的这名武官
is her childhood friend who grew up
是芙蓉妃的青梅竹马
in the same homeland.
他们来自同一个地方
I heard that this childhood friend was praised for his valor
我听说她这位青梅竹马 在最近的一场战役当中
for defeating foreign troops in the recent battle.
因为打败 异族兵团的英勇行径受到表彰
He was offered a reward
他获得了赏赐
and strongly wished for the bestowment of Concubine Fuyou.
而他强烈表达出 想要得到芙蓉妃的意愿
He was probably hoping for this
他很可能在他们
since he was living in his homeland.
还待在家乡的时候就有这种期望了
A soldier doesn't have the social standing to propose to a princess.
一名武官的社会地位 不足以向公主求婚
Even so, she ended up entering the rear palace…
尽管如此 她最后进入了后宫
The princess loved her childhood friend as well.
公主也深爱着她的青梅竹马
That's why she purposefully messed up her dance
所以她故意在舞蹈表演时出错
so that the Emperor wouldn't be interested in her.
这样皇上就不会对她感兴趣
As planned, she had no night visits from the Emperor,
如她所愿 皇上从来没临幸过她
and she remains chaste.
她仍然保有完璧之身
But there was no guarantee that the Emperor wouldn't prevent Concubine Fuyou
但这无法保证皇上不会把芙蓉妃
from falling into the hands of another man.
赏赐给其他人
So she pretended to have somnambulance…
所以她假装得了梦游症…
That was a possibility with the Emperor.
皇上的确有可能这么做
You never know with Him.
他让人无法捉摸
The battlegrounds with the foreign troops are to the east.
和异族作战的战场位于东侧
And Concubine Fuyou was dancing every night at…
而芙蓉妃每晚跳舞的地点…
The Eastern Gate?
东大门？
She was probably praying for his safe return.
她很可能在祈求他安全归来
Though this is just speculation.
但这只是我的猜测
-Hey, Maomao. -Yes.
-猫猫 -是的
If I said I feel jealous of Concubine Fuyou,
如果我说我嫉妒芙蓉妃
would I be a terrible woman?
会显得我很糟糕吗？
Concubine Fuyou was beautiful that night.
芙蓉妃那晚好美
Almost as if she was a different woman
跟我在白天见到的
than the simple princess I saw during the day.
平凡公主模样大不相同
I don't think that at all.
我一点都不这么认为
-Let's go. -Yes, ma'am.
-走吧 -是 娘娘
If love makes a woman beautiful,
如果爱会让一个女人变美
what kind of medicine would it be?
那会是个什么样的药方啊？
We would like to request something from the rumored apothecary.
我有事想拜托传闻中的药师大人
PREVIEW OF NEXT EPISODE
（下集预告）
Next episode, "The Threat."
下一集 《威胁》
Subtitle translation by: Yukimi Ohashi
字幕翻译：欧德慧